William Walden Rubey Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1915-1974 (Box 38-95)
  - Mohole project (Box 54)
    - National Science Foundation
      - Press releases, 1963-1966
      - Reports, 1965-1966, (2 folders)
      - Selection of contractor (Box 63)
        - Contract, 1962
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1961-1963
    - Newspaper clippings, 1958-1971, (3 folders)
  - National Academy of Sciences
    - Atomic Energy Commission fellowship program, 1949-1951, (2 folders)
    - Awards
      - Antonio Feltrini Award, 1965
      - Arthur L. Day Prize, 1971-1972
    - Centennial program, 1963-1964
    - Committees
      - Ad Hoc Committee to Consider Merger of Geophysics and Geology sections, 1967
      - Committee on Arrangements, 1946-1950, 1957
      - Committee on Arthur L. Day Bequest, 1966-1972, (6 folders)
      - Committee on the Endowment of the Academy, 1965-1966 (Box 64)
      - Committee on Government Relations, 1962
      - Committee on the Murray Fund, 1948-1951
      - Committee on Natural Resources, 1961-1963, (3 folders)
      - Committee on Nominations, 1947-1972, (2 folders)
      - Committee on Polar Research, 1958
      - Committee on Science and Public Policy
        - Background materials, 1962-1963
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1961-1964, (3 folders) (Box 65)
        - National Institute of Health, 1963
        - Newspaper clippings and press releases, 1962-1963
        - Reports, 1963-1964, (4 folders)
        - Statements before congressional committees, 1963 (Box 66)
        - Study on computer use
          - Correspondence, 1962-1963
          - Reports, 1964, (3 folders)
      - Committee on Scientific Personnel in the Armed Services, 1950-1951
      - Committee on SST-Sonic Boom, 1968
      - Library Committee, 1946
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1952
      - Search Committee for a Director of the United States Geological Survey, 1965-1971
      - Selection Committee for the G. K. Warren Prize, 1969-1974
      - Standing Committees on Meetings, 1947-1948
    - Conferences and symposia
      - Conference on Major Biologic Innovations and the Geologic Record, 1961
      - Conference at Rancho Santa Fe, Santa Fe, N.Mex., 1961 (Box 67)
      - International Geophysical Year
        - Geo-chemical discussion, 1956
        - Symposium on results, 1963
      - International Scientific, 1964-1968
      - Symposium on Basic Research, 1959
    - Council for the Academy, 1954, 1965
    - Editorial board, 1947-1957
    - Environmental studies board, 1967-1968
    - Lists of publications, undated
    - Meetings, 1947-1969, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1947-1973
    - Space Science Board
      - Correspondence, 1968-1973
      - Meetings
        - General, 1969-1972, undated
        - Lunar and Planetary Missions Board, 1970
        - Summer study program, 1962-1970, (5 folders) (Box 68)
    - State University of New York, Stony Brook, N.Y., 1967
    - Unidentified flying objects, 1968-1969
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration
    - Ad Hoc Working Group on Apollo Scientific Experiments and Training
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1962-1963
      - Reports, 1962
    - Earth Resources Technology Satellites, geology panel
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1970-1971
      - Lists of panel members and notes, 1971
      - Proposal evaluations, 1971 (Box 69)
    - Institute for Space Studies, 1961-1970
    - Lunar and Planetary Missions Board, 1969-1971
    - Miscellany, 1959-1973, (2 folders)
    - Space Sciences Steering Committee, 1960-1963
    - Viking project, 1969-1970, (2 folders)
  - National Conference on UNESCO
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1947
    - Printed materials, 1946-1947
  - National Research Council
    - Annual reports for 1943-1946, 1953-1958
    - Atomic Energy Commission fellowship program, 1947-1949
    - Committees
      - Advisory Committee for Office of Naval Research on Geophysics
        - Agendas and minutes of meetings, 1947-1950
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1947-1950
        - Notes and miscellany, 1947-1950 (Box 70)
      - Committee on Hydrology, 1932-1936
      - Committee on Mineral Science and Technology, 1966-1970
      - Committee on Radioactivity, 1946-1950
      - Committee on Review Articles, 1950-1958, (2 folders)
      - Committee on a Treatise on Marine Ecology and Paleoecology, 1953
      - Interdivisional Committee on Borderland Fields in Geology, Physics, and Chemistry
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1936-1938, (3 folders)
        - Notes, 1936
        - Projects, 1936
        - Reports, 1937-1938
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1932-1968, (2 folders)
    - Glossary of Nuclear Terms, 1949-1950 (Box 71)
    - Meetings, 1967-1968
    - Panel on earthquake modification, 1972, (2 folder)
  - National Roster of Scientific and Technical Personnel, 1940-1960, (2 folders)
  - National Science Foundation
    - Conference on Theoretical Geophysics, 1956
    - Divisional Committee for Mathematical, Physical, and Engineering Sciences, 1951-1955
    - Fellowship program, 1956-1963, 1973, (3 folders)
    - Legislation of interest (Box 72)
      - Civil Rights Act, 1964
      - Kilgore bill, 1943-1945
      - Lists of congressional committees, 1965
      - National Science Foundation Act, 1960-1965
    - Miscellany, 1960-1965
    - National Register, 1966
    - National Science Board
      - Advisory Committee for Minerals Research, 1961
      - Appointments and nominations to board, 1957-1966
      - Congressional hearings
        - 1963-1966, (5 folders)
        - 1966, (2 folders) (Box 73)
      - Memoranda, 1952, 1962
    - Miscellany, 1963-1974
  - National Science Foundation
    - Organizational charts, 1964-1965
    - Panels
      - Advisory Panel on Minerals Research, 1952-1956, (2 folders)
      - Panel on Earth Sciences, 1952-1957
    - Research programs
      - Oceanography studies, 1964-1965
      - Proposals, 1956-1971
    - Review journal in geophysics, 1962
    - University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, Institute of Geophysics, 1955-1958, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - National Science Planning Board, 1958
  - Office of Science and Technology
    - Ad Hoc Panel on the Safety of Underground Testing, 1968-1969, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1962-1964
  - Personal file
    - Biographical and bibliographical information, 1973
    - Calendars, 1966-1973, (2 folders)
    - Notes re informal geological discussions held at Rubey's home, 1953-1958, undated, (4 folders)
    - Memorial service, 1974 (Box 75)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Science Award Committee, 1968-1970
  - President's Commission on the National Medal of Science, 1961-1973
  - Rubey Conference on Crustal Evolution, 1973
  - Science Service, 1955-1967, (2 folders)
  - Seismic Study Group, 1948
  - Society for Environmental Geochemistry and Health, 1968-1972, (2 folders)
  - Society of the Sigma Xi, 1960-1967
  - United States Geological Survey
    - Branches
      - General geology, 1959, undated
      - Northern Rocky Mountains, 1961-1963
      - Paleontology and stratigraphy, 1949-1956, undated
    - Committees (Box 76)
      - Advisory Committee on Geochemistry of Carbonaceous Materials
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1952-1955
        - Project descriptions
          - Revisions, 1954, undated, (2 folders)
          - Summaries, 1953-1954, (2 folders)
      - Geological Names Committee
        - Carbonaceous nomenclature
        - Stratigraphic nomenclature
          - American Commission on Stratigraphic Nomenclature, 1951-1952, undated
          - Background materials, 1915-1955, undated, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1915-1961, undated
          - Minutes of meetings, 1930, 1961
          - Notes, undated
          - Reports, 1956, undated
          - Revision of nomenclature code, 1963-1964 (Box 77)
      - Laboratory Program Committee, 1955-1956, (3 folders)
      - Library Committee, 1935-1949, undated
      - Steering Committee for the Revision of the Data of Geochemistry, 1955-1959, undated
      - Structure Symbols Committee, 1947-1952, undated
    - Correspondence and memoranda
      - Areal and nonmetalliferous section, 1928-1939, (2 folders)
      - Geologists
        - Chief geologist, 1924-1953
        - Director of survey, 1930-1952
        - Others, 1922-1961, undated, (4 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1923-1969, undated, (3 folders)
      - Oil and gas section, 1921-1924, (5 folders) (Box 78)
      - State geological surveys
        - Illinois, 1928-1930, (3 folders)
        - Kansas, 1924-1925
    - Field work
      - Administrative
        - Equipment and employees, 1930-1954, undated, (3 folders)
        - Estimated expenses, 1931-1939, 1947
      - Projects
        - Ashland graphite-vanadium project, 1943
        - Black Hills rim project, 1923-1928, undated, (2 folders)
        - Cokeville project (Box 79)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1945-1969, (6 folders)
          - Expenses, 1950-1967, (2 folders)
          - Lists of sample specimens, undated
            - Group A
            - Group B, (2 folders)
            - Group C (Box 80)
            - Group D
            - Group E
            - Group F1
            - Group F2
              - Colorado-Kansas
              - Montana-Wyoming
            - Indexes
            - Manganese-bearing rocks
            - Miscellaneous special categories
            - Phosphate rocks
          - Rock salt
          - Saline deposits
          - Miscellany, 1953, undated
          - Reports, 1949-1967, (3 folders)
        - Magnetic anomalies in western Wyoming study
          - Aero-magnetic profiles, 1962
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 81)
          - Graphs and maps, undated
        - Mapping project
          - Correspondence, 1947-1948
          - Miscellany, 1947
          - Notes, 1947, undated
          - Reports and memoranda, 1943-1957, undated, (4 folders)
        - Paleotectonic map series, 1945-1963, undated, (4 folders)
        - Phosphate project
          - Background information, 1947-1950, undated
          - Charts and diagrams, undated
          - Chemical analyses, 1932-1951
          - Conferences, 1947
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1935-1955 (Box 82)
          - Lists of sample specimens, 1942, undated, (5 folders)
          - Maps, undated
          - Monthly reports, 1947-1948
          - Notes, undated
            - Computations
            - General
            - Thin sections and additional chemical tests
          - Trench plots, 1942, (2 folders)
        - Pierre Shale project (Box 83)
          - Chemical analyses, 1956-1959, (2 folders)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1956-1959, (2 folders)
          - Meetings, 1956-1957, undated
          - Monthly reports, 1957-1959, undated
          - Notes, undated
            - Aluminous clays
            - Iron-rich rocks
            - Preliminary data on geochemistry of Pierre shale, 1957-1962
        - Rhenium investigations, 1939-1943
        - Rocky Ford oil project
          - Charts and maps, undated
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1925
          - Lists of sample specimens, 1920, undated
          - Mechanical analyses of samples, 1923, undated
          - Notes, 1920-1924, undated, (3 folders)
          - Reports, 1923-1925, undated
        - Strategic minerals program (Box 84)
          - Miscellaneous minerals, 1941-1943, undated
          - Vanadium investigations
            - Correspondence and memoranda, 1940-1943, (5 folders)
            - Lists of sample specimens, 1942-1943
            - Miscellany, undated
            - Newspaper clippings, 1942-1943
            - Notes
              - General, undated
              - Vanadiferous shale, 1943
            - Press releases, 1943, undated
            - Printed materials re investigations, 1943
            - Reports
              - Drafts, 1942, (2 folders)
              - Printed version, 1942 (Box 85)
            - Trench plots, 1938
        - Tertiary mapping of southwest Wyoming, 1956-1957
        - Trace elements investigations
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1944-1952, (2 folders)
          - Notes, undated
          - Reports and other materials, 1944-1947, undated
        - Uranium investigations, 1947-1950, undated
    - Miscellany, drawings and notes, 1947-1950, undated
    - Monthly reports, 1920-1942, (5 folders)
    - Monthly statistics, 1924-1941, (2 folders)
    - Other projects (Box 86)
      - Aerial photography, 1945-1948, undated
      - Atomic bomb testing, 1946
      - Black Shale conference, 1954-1956, (2 folders)
      - Chesapeake Bay, 1943-1947
      - Civil Defense relocation, 1955
      - Clinch River area, Virginia, 1934
      - Geochemical Prospecting Unit, 1946-1951
      - Geology of radioactive raw materials, 1946
      - Gravity stations
        - Background information, 1939, undated, (2 folders)
        - Charts and maps, undated
        - Density analyses, 1939
        - Descriptions, undated
        - Isostatic reductions, undated (Box 87)
        - Memoranda, 1939-1940
        - Notes, undated
          - Compilations
          - Data, (2 folders)
          - General
        - Statistics
        - Tables, modified Bouguer anomalies
      - Hydrology, 1936-1939, undated
      - Magnesium Incendiary Bomb Extinguishers, 1942
      - Mine and mill product analysis, 1952
      - Nuclear Energy Program, undated
      - Oceanography, 1960
      - Parabola studies
        - Charts and diagrams, undated
        - Memoranda, 1944
        - Notes, undated
          - Alternatives to imaginary construction
          - Apparent dip and thickness, (2 folders) (Box 88)
          - Ellipses and hyperbolas, undated
          - General
      - Plant fossils, 1923-1934, 1958, undated
      - Pleistocene-Recent boundary studies, 1951-1952
      - Research Board for National Security, 1944-1945
      - Soil Conservation Service, 1935-1940
      - Spectrography, 1943-1951, undated
    - Research notes
      - Alpine-Fremont lake, undated
      - Bassett and Jolibois, undated
      - Calculations vs. reserve estimates, undated
      - Canyons, undated
      - Data relating to rivers
        - Analyses of river profiles, 1929
        - Bed-rock, Mississippi and Illinois, undated
        - Comparisons, Illinois, Missouri and Mississippi, undated
        - Distances and elevations, Illinois and Desplaines, undated
        - General information, Colorado and Missouri, 1928-1938, undated (Box 89)
        - Meanders, undated
        - Sheet wash, undated
      - Diagrams of tetrahedrons, undated
      - Kazokov, A. V., 1936-1937
      - Magnesite, dolomite, and parasepiolete, undated
    - Organic matter, 1936
    - P2O5 reserves, undated, (2 folders)
      - Probable error, undated
    - Recalculations of S and H, undated
    - Sublette ridge, undated
    - World War II activities
      - Director's paper on wartime activities, 1943
      - Personnel placement, 1942-1943
      - Postwar planning
        - Memoranda and reports, 1943, undated
        - Notes, undated
      - Publications re use of geology during war, 1920, 1941-1943, (2 folders) (Box 90)
      - Small war plants, 1944
      - Staff lists, 1943
      - United States Army Corps of Engineers, undated
      - War minerals investigations, 1942-1943
      - Water resources, 1941-1942
  - United States-Japan Committee on Scientific Cooperation
    - Background materials re Japanese scientific research, 1961
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1961-1963, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 91)
    - Meetings
      - 1961-1962, (7 folders)
      - 1962-1963, (6 folders) (Box 92)
    - Projects, 1963
  - United States National Committee on Geology, 1961-1965, (3 folders) (Box 93)
  - Universities Space Research Association
    - Bylaws and organizational information, 1969-1973
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1968-1971, (3 folders)
    - Meetings, 1970-1974
    - Notes, 1969-1971, undated
    - Proposal for contract renewal, 1971
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Calif.
    - Academic Senate
    - Advisory Committee on Selection of a President, 1966-1967
    - Research Committee, 1964-1971, (2 folders)
    - All-University Faculty Conferences, 1961-1967, undated (Box 94)
    - Bio-bibliographies, 1961-1973
    - Committees
      - Advisory Committee on Astronomy, 1963-1970
      - Interdepartmental Committee on Geochemistry, 1962-1973
      - Other committees, 1962-1968
    - Department of Geology
      - Curriculum studies, 1969-1973
      - Davis campus, 1961-1963
      - Newsletters, 1967-1973, (2 folders)
      - Staffing, 1967-1968, undated
      - Survey of graduate education, 1962-1963
    - Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Sciences
      - Correspondence, 1954-1971
      - Reports, 1960-1970
    - Miscellany, 1965-1974
  - University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minn., 1959-1960 (Box 95)
  - University of Missouri, Columbia, Mo., 1963-1967, undated
  - Vetlesen Prize Award, 1960-1962, 1971
  - Washington Academy of Sciences, 1930-1972, (2 folders)
  - Yale University Press, 1958-1965, undated
  - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute, Woods Hole, Mass.
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1959-1973
    - Lists of honorary trustees, 1966-1970
    - Membership directories, 1967-1973
    - Notes and miscellany, 1970-1972, undated
    - Reports, 1972
- Oversize, 1962-1966 (Box OV 1)
  Graphs concerning earthquakes and well-head pressure in Colorado.
  Organized and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Subject file (Box OV 1)
    - Denver earthquakes
      - United States Army Corps of Engineers
        - Charts, 1962-1966 (Container 46)